<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Codefellows | Philip Q Nguyen's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ninjacorner.com/blog/categories/codefellows/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ninjacorner.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-27T22:59:43-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ninjacorner.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Philip Q Nguyen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Ready for Codefellows' Ruby on Rails Accelerator]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ninjacorner.com/blog/2014/09/14/getting-ready-for-codefellows-ruby-on-rails-accelerator/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-14T15:49:09-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ninjacorner.com/blog/2014/09/14/getting-ready-for-codefellows-ruby-on-rails-accelerator</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the past few months, I have:</p>

<ul>
<li>finished all of my MBA requirements at Kwansei Gakuin University</li>
<li>left Japan and return to Reno, Nevada</li>
<li>moved to Seattle, Washington</li>
<li>completed the one month Codefellows foundations bootcamp</li>
<li>been accepted for the two months Codefellows Ruby on Rails Accelerator</li>
</ul>


<p>Phew! That&rsquo;s quite a life style change. As you can see, there are two types of modules in Codefellows that I have attended and will be attending; the foundations bootcamp, and the more advance Ruby on Rails Accelerator.</p>

<p>The foundations bootcamp was an intensive intro to CS and web development.<!-- more --> I had about a year worth of experience developing Ruby on Rails apps, and everything that was taught in class quickly made sense to me. What I really got out of it was the structure and best practices which I never knew before. In addition to that, the ability now to write pure JavaScript was a huge plus.</p>

<p>Starting tomorrow, I will be attending the first day of the Codefellows Ruby on Rails Accelerator. Again with this, I hope to absorb in best practices, and to obtain a deeper understanding of the magic that happens inside the Rails framework.</p>

<p>The whole day today, I have been preparing my computer by installing and/or updating a whole bunch of development software. Notably, Codefellows required that I had to uninstall RVM and instead install rbenv. I&rsquo;ve never used rbenv before, so this will be a new learning experience for me.</p>

<p>In any case, I plan to keep updating this blog with my experiences at Codefellows.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
